<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:38:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kaushik-iyer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First blog entry here</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/blog/first/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:38:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/blog/first/</guid><description>&lt;p>First blog entry here. I dont think I&amp;rsquo;m learned enough to actually write informative blogs, so this space might just look like tweets for now. Anyway, creating a portfolio website was something that I had been thinking of for months, and was the first thing I decided to do once my winter break started, and thankfully that did happen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soccer Drop In Statistics Logger</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/soccer-drop-in-statistics-logger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/soccer-drop-in-statistics-logger/</guid><description>&lt;p>This was a personal project on which I worked at during summer 2024. Since a long time I had been wanting to develop a proper project from scratch which was not a youtube tutorial or a walkthrough. All of the ideas for this project were things that I wanted to implement. The whole backend and frontend has been done by myself, and since I like working on backend more, unfortunately the frontend aesthetics and accessibility are not upto the mark. Anyway, the frontend is in React, and backend built in python&amp;rsquo;s FASTAPI. The scores are regularly updated from a third party API through websockets, the nearby grounds are fetched by using the user&amp;rsquo;s location and Google Places API. The website also performs Google OAuth 2.0 through the frontend itself. A large part of the project also involved figuring out the hosting aspects, including getting a domain, and hosting the frontend as well as the backend folders. I eventually got a domain free for a year through name.com, hosted the frontend through cloudflare pages in their free tier, and got to host the backend in heroku for 2 years through Github&amp;rsquo;s Student Developer Pack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traveling Salesman Problem Optimization</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/traveling-salesman-problem-optimization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/traveling-salesman-problem-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;p>Built this group project as part of Cornell&amp;rsquo;s Applications of Parallel Computers course (CS 5220), where we tackled the classic Traveling Salesman Problem using various optimization techniques. The goal was to push the boundaries of what&amp;rsquo;s possible with parallel computing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We implemented four different approaches - from exact solutions using Brute Force and Dynamic Programming to heuristic methods like Greedy and Genetic algorithms. The real challenge was optimizing these for parallel execution using OpenMP and CUDA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Document Conversion Assistant</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/experience/cornell-sds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/experience/cornell-sds/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="making-education-accessible-through-technology">Making Education Accessible Through Technology&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In my role at Cornell University, I work to bridge the gap between traditional educational materials and accessible formats, ensuring that all students have equal access to learning resources:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Transform complex textbooks and academic materials into accessible formats using advanced document processing techniques&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Utilize Microsoft Word&amp;rsquo;s advanced features to optimize document layouts, headers, footers, and references for various accessibility needs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collaborate daily through Microsoft Teams to coordinate task assignments and ensure timely delivery of converted materials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Work closely with disability services to understand and implement specific accessibility requirements for different learning needs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintain detailed documentation of conversion processes and best practices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participate in regular training sessions to stay updated with the latest accessibility standards and tools&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This position has deepened my understanding of inclusive design principles and the critical role of technology in creating equitable educational experiences.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GreenTech Registry on Blockchain</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/greentech-registry-on-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/greentech-registry-on-blockchain/</guid><description>&lt;p>I developed this project during my first semester at Cornell, as a part of my M.Eng Project for the Systems Engineering faculty. This project aims to solve some of the shortcomings of existing greentech technologies such as lack of verifiability and difficulty in tracking orders by leveraging the strengths of blockchain technology and its features of immutability, verifiability, and transparency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And since this was a part of an academic research paper as well, extensive efforts were put into performance testing of the platform, which included performing load testing under multiple simultaneous users calling computationally intensive functionalities such as create project, and upload images. These tests were performed under different request body sizes and multiple such calls. The test suites and visualizations were custom developed in Python, primarily using modules such as asyncio, locust, and matplotlib for concurrency, load test configurations, and visualizations respectively. These were custom made because Postman&amp;rsquo;s collection run functionality did not cater to this particular use case.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replicated Key-Value Store with Paxos Consensus</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/replicated-key-value-store-with-paxos-consensus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/replicated-key-value-store-with-paxos-consensus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developed a robust distributed key-value store that implements fundamental distributed systems concepts, progressing through multiple stages of complexity:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Started with implementing an exactly-once RPC protocol on top of an asynchronous network, ensuring reliable communication between nodes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enhanced the system with fault-tolerance capabilities through a primary-backup replication protocol&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implemented Paxos consensus algorithm to ensure strong consistency across replicas, allowing the system to handle node failures and network partitions gracefully&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Built comprehensive test suites to verify system behavior under various failure scenarios and message ordering conditions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The project demonstrates practical implementation of distributed systems theory, focusing on:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skima.ai</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/experience/skima/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/experience/skima/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="building-the-future-of-ai-powered-recruitment">Building the Future of AI-Powered Recruitment&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My journey at Skima.ai was transformative, working at the intersection of recruitment technology and artificial intelligence. As one of the early engineering interns at this ambitious startup, I had the opportunity to work on critical infrastructure and performance optimization that directly impacted our user experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spearheaded several key initiatives that significantly improved our platform&amp;rsquo;s performance:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Engineered a 70% improvement in query speed through sophisticated optimization of Ruby on Rails ActiveRecord with PostgreSQL, transforming our candidate listing pages from sluggish to near-instantaneous&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Architected and implemented an asynchronous processing system using Sidekiq workers and cron jobs, dramatically improving system responsiveness for our recruitment partners&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Led the migration of our critical workflow to AWS Lambda, achieving a 50% boost in processing speed and enabling real-time data-driven decision making&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrated and fine-tuned multiple third-party APIs including Stripe for payments and Greenhouse for ATS integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed robust web scraping solutions using Python and Selenium to expand our market analysis capabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implemented advanced LLM prompt engineering using OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s Ruby gem, automating diverse data generation and enhancing our AI-powered features&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Working in a fast-paced startup environment taught me invaluable lessons about rapid iteration, cross-functional collaboration, and the importance of building scalable solutions. Each feature release directly impacted our user acquisition and retention metrics, providing immediate feedback on our engineering decisions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NurseBot: Healthcare Automation System</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/nursebot-healthcare-automation-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/projects/nursebot-healthcare-automation-system/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developed an innovative healthcare automation system combining robotics and IoT to assist medical staff in routine patient care tasks. The project integrated multiple technologies to create a comprehensive solution for patient monitoring and medication delivery. It is a line following robot, which successfully navigates across &amp;lsquo;+&amp;rsquo; junctions, performs a U-turn at the end and starts sensory activity when the finger is placed. The value is updated immediately on the Blynk app&amp;rsquo;s displays, and then the robot automatically follows the same path back to the starting position.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DeepCytes</title><link>https://kaushik-iyer.com/experience/deepcytes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kaushik-iyer.com/experience/deepcytes/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="diving-into-digital-forensics-and-market-fraud-investigation">Diving into Digital Forensics and Market Fraud Investigation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At DeepCytes, I immersed myself in the fascinating world of cybersecurity and financial fraud investigation. This internship provided me with hands-on experience in digital forensics and market analysis:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Configured and deployed sophisticated forensic tools using Docker containers, ensuring consistent and reliable investigation environments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participated in high-stakes investigations into stock market fraud, developing analytical skills and attention to detail&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collaborated with senior investigators to analyze complex financial data patterns and identify potential fraudulent activities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gained practical experience with GitHub for version control and collaborative forensic tool development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learned to work with sensitive financial data while maintaining strict confidentiality protocols&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This experience gave me valuable insights into the intersection of technology and financial security, teaching me the importance of precision and thoroughness in security-critical applications.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>